

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Project management
Client needs analysis
French translation & localisation
Technical & Medical translation
Pedagogical Design with SMEs
Storyboarding
Edit and Proofreading
2D animation using Vyond
Video and audio editing
Media production & integration
Data management (SCORM protocol)
Quality control & assurance

# SOFTWARES

Articulate 360 Office 360 Adobe Creative Suite Vyond ClickUp and many more

# CONTACT

P: +1 514 677 0241 E: veronique@octod.ca W: www.octod.ca/

# VÉRONIQUE CÉLESTE

E-LEARNING CONSULTANT

# **ABOUT**

Years of working in the non-profit sector have allowed me to develop my persuasive skills as well as my ability to positively influence people in order to motivate them and lead them to action. In addition, I have good judgment, analytical skills and critical thinking skills. My studies have given me an eye for detail and have in no way diminished my love of precision and finding the right words. For the past few years, I have specialized in the design, adaptation and media integration of online training materials.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

E-LEARNING CONSULTANT & HEAD OF LOCALISATION OCTO D | 2016 - Present



FOUNDER & HEAD TRANSLATOR
Hexarium Translation Services | 2011 - Present





# **EDUCATION**

D.E.S.S TRANSLATION (EN TO FR) Université de Montréal | 2011

BACHELOR IN LIBERAL ARTS Université de Montréal | 2003

# WHO'S TRUSTING ME





















Among many others

## SOME RECENT PROJECTS

#### 2022-23 Product School

Production of several online training course using Storyline 360 and Adobe Premiere Pro, and implementation of the courses on Teachables (on-going).

#### 2022-23 Indigenous Primary Health Care Council (IPHCC)

Production of two 2-hour online training courses including videos, animation, gamification elements and numerous activities (on-going).

# 2022 Connex Health

Translation and proofreading of the whole Simplify Prior Authorisation initiative's website within a month and a half window (around thirty thousand words).

#### 2022 Canadian Skin Patient Alliance

Translation and proofreading of "A report on the acne patient experience in Canada" within a 2 weeks window (around seven thousand words).

### 2022 Institut national de santé publique du Québec (INSPQ)

Design and production of a two 2-hour online training courses including animation, gamification elements and numerous activities. This project included six "You are the Hero" type scenarios inspired by the aesthetics of comic books.

#### 2021-23 Mercer USA & Canada

Production of several OE and NH presentations using Storyline 360 (on-going)

#### 2020-23 Adopt4Life

Head translator for Ontario's Association for kin, customary care, and adoptive parents and caregivers (Adopt4Life). Translation of internal and external documents including website, worksheets, communications, etc. for the last 4 years (on-going).

#### 2020 SPUR CHANGE Inter-Council Network

Production of a 3-hour online training course includind localisation, accessibility compliance and quality control.

#### 2019 Dawson College

Localisation of a session equivalent to eight courses in two languages, i.e. thirty hours of training within a six-month production window. The training modules were created in partnership with Dawson's internal team, coached by Octo D.

# 2018-19 RW&Co

Edit and proofreading of their OFFSIDE magazine French translations.

#### 2014-23 The Montreal Office

Freelance editing and proofreading for multiple clients of this marketing agency, including: Canadian Tire, FYi doctors, Tourism Nova Scotia, Skip the Dishes, Oyster Bay, Herzig, Fido, Dare Foods, North Paw (dog food), Canada Sound, etc.

# PAST PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

1998 - 2010 Work with children and youth within several non-profit organizations:

- CRÉ de Montréal, youth forum: development officer internship
- Maison des Jeunes par la Grand'Porte, Montreal: intervention and coordination
- Maison des jeunes le Squatt d'Ahuntsic, Montreal : intervention
- Centre Sainte-Catherine d'Alexandrie, Montreal: intervention and animation
- Centre Lajeunesse, Montreal
- Services des loisirs, Hull